hey guys so we want to solve the radius
of this circle first let's find the
center of the circle and this right here
is going to be the radius I first
thought was maybe it equals 1 but it
doesn't cuz if we bring this down that's
not in the middle here cuz the edge of
the circle is not in the middle either
so we can't really do that next let's
look at this diagonal here we can
actually find out what this diagonal is
cuz this is a right angle so if we call
this side a this side B and this side C
we know that a s + b s is equal to c^2 a
right here is equal to 2 the B is the
same as this right here so it's equal to
2 and then C we'll just leave a c^ s 2 s
is 4 + 2^ 2 is 4 is equal to c^ 2 4 + 4
is 8 we square root both sides on the
left hand side we can break < TK of8
into < of 4 * < TK of two and theun of 4
is 2 and on the right hand side it just
becomes C so we can clean this stuff up
up here and let's put 2 < tk2 right here
for this piece of the diagonal let's get
rid of all this stuff unfortunately the
diameter here is not 2 < tk2 because it
doesn't go all the way to the corner but
we can say that the rest of the diagonal
right up here is also 2 < tk2 so we can
calculate the diagonal of the big square
and it's going going to be equal to the
2 < tk2 plus the 2 < tk2 which is just 4
< tk2 and we can put a box around that
let's clean this all up a little bit and
this right here is the radius we'll call
that R this is what we're trying to
solve for so we know this we know this
we just got to find this piece right
here that's not too bad because we can
make a square right here we know each of
these are equal to the radius as well so
we can call both the sides of this
Square R then we can do another diagonal
we'll move this R over to here and if we
make the diagonal equal to C then we
know that R 2 + R2 = c^2 well R2 + r 2
is 2 r s we can square root both sides
the left hand side can be broken out
into < TK of 2 * < TK of R 2 and the
right hand side would just bequ < TK of
c squ and then squ of R squ is just R
andun of c s is just C and we can smush
these together and we have squ > of 2 R
is equal to C up here was our diagonal C
so we can change that into < tk2 R clean
things up a little bit and now what do
we have big diagonal again this time
it's equal to this diagonal here the 2 <
tk2 plus the r plus the < tk2 r and we
can put a box around that but we know
that the big diagonal has to equal the
big diagonal so we're just going to set
the 4 < tk2 for this side of the big
diagonal equal to all of this and now we
only have one variable R and one
equation so once we solve for R we know
the answer we can subtract 2 < tk2 from
both sides the left hand side becomes 2
< tk2 the right hand side that's gone so
it's just this right here and we can
scoot these over and let's Factor an R
out of the right hand side so R * what
gives us R that's one so R * 1 is r and
then R * what gives us < tk2 R that's
going to be < tk2 so if you imagine
Distributing this it would bring us back
to where we were up here so we factored
out the r then on the left hand side
leave that as 2 < tk2 the 1+ < tk2 is
just a number so we can divide both
sides by that number and we end up with
r being equal to 2 < tk2 over 1 + < tk2
and we can plug it into a calculator and
get a decimal approximation of 17157 and
that keeps going it's irrational and now
we have the answer to our question the
radius is approximately
17157 and we can put a box around that
how exciting